BORJAN PETRESKI

e-mail: petreski_borjan@hotmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/borjanpetreski/

tel. +389 78 401 985



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

With five years of diverse experience and a long way ahead of me to deepen my knowledge, I would describe myself as eager for new opportunities, challenges, and continuous gain and improvement of new skills. Working in a dynamic environment modelled me into a diligent but flexible person, persevering in difficult situations, welcoming differences in opinion with an open mind and fair consideration. Constantly overcoming the arising problems, I have expanded my experience in managing customized projects with diverse business requirements from disparate technical spheres ranging from Industrial IoT and Digital Marketing, to Pharmaceutical and Paper Machine industries.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering – Energy and Environment

Ss. Cyril and Methodius University, Skopje, Republic of N. Macedonia

Graduation Date: April 2017

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering – Energy and Environment

Ss. Cyril and Methodius University, Skopje, Republic of Macedonia

Graduation Date: September 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

IIBA - Entry Certificate in Business Analysis (ECBA)

Issued: June 2020 · No Expiration Date

Scrum.org – Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO)

Issued: March 2020 · No Expiration Date

Scrum.org – Professional Scrum Master (PSM)

Issued: February 2020 · No Expiration Date

Microsoft Certified - Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104)

Issued: February 2021 · February 2023

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Service Delivery Manager, Symphony Digital, Skopje, N Macedonia Software design and development for the world's most innovative brands. 05/2022 - Present

- Collaborating with key stakeholders, identifying the needs, and translating them into product requirements.
- Leading a&d and delivery teams, facilitating team organization to meet important milestones.
- Preparing release plans, ranged delivery roadmaps and team engagement plans.
- Creating team compositions to drive the product development.
- Defining and managing product's Value Streams.
- Owning, managing, and prioritizing the highest value first Product Backlog.
- Enabling specifications for Product Backlog Items with technical dependencies.
- Managing scrum ceremonies, following agile patterns and best practices.
- Overseeing the delivery and release process; assessing the customer feedback. Products (under NDA): Music Industry (Fortune 100), Artificial Intelligence (Startup)

IT Project Manager, Sopro, Skopje, N Macedonia

Social Prospecting, B2B Sales, Digital Marketing, Prospecting Services 06/2021 – 05/2022 (1 year)

- Implement agile project management strategies.
- Ensure projects are delivered on time.
- Communicate progress, success, and issues with stakeholders at all levels.
- Manage resources both internally and externally to optimize project delivery.
- Work with the UX team to develop briefs and prototypes.
- Product ownership, deployment management, release management.
- Creating and maintaining documentation of processes and practices.
- Product documentation.

Products: Sodastream, Client Portal, Writers Portal, Toolset, Aslan

Agile Project Manager, Nebb Solutions, Skopje, N. Macedonia

Industrial IoT, engineering, and consulting services for the oil & gas, pulp & paper, and the paper machine clothing industries.

02/2020 - 06/2021(1 year 4 months)

- Provided product analytics and strategic recommendations.
- Forecasted and managed projects in an agile workflow, within budgeted plan.
- Created ad-hoc reporting on biweekly results to management identifying key drivers.
- Developed new product launch plans with vendor teams to increase brand interaction.
- Integrated agile workflow into a waterfall model, increasing productivity and morale.
- Researched, analysed, designed, and evaluated technical solutions.
- Participated with peers and represented the business on project teams.
- Managed product ownership of projects from beginning to end.
- Managed a team and participated in team project planning.

Projects: PMC - VaporXS Steambox; NMS - Qlarm

Associate DevOps Engineer, Nebb Solutions, Skopje, N. Macedonia

Industrial IoT, engineering, and consulting services for the oil & gas, pulp & paper, and the paper machine clothing industries.

09/2020 – 06/2021 (6 months)

- Building and setting up new development tools and infrastructure.
- Understanding the needs of stakeholders and conveying this to developers.
- Working on ways to automate and improve development and release processes.
- Testing and examining code written by others and analyzing results.
- Ensuring that systems are safe and secure against cybersecurity threats.
- Identifying technical problems and developing software updates and 'fixes'.
- Working with software developers and software engineers to ensure that development follows established processes and works as intended.
- Planning out projects and being involved in project management decisions.

Projects: NMS – Qlarm, LearnLab

Research and Development Team Lead, Nebb Solutions, Skopje, N. Macedonia *Industrial IoT, engineering, and consulting services for the oil & gas, pulp & paper, and the paper machine clothing industries.*

08/2019 – 02/2020 (7 months)

- Used various software for Computer-aided Engineering (CAE): CFD & FEA.
- Performed Autodesk Vault maintenance and implement advanced workflows.
- Estimated time and costs required for project completion.
- Researched and implemented software improvements.
- Created detailed design documentation.
- Created drawings, parts, and assemblies.
- Produced final design specifications.

Projects: Finishing Machine for Paper Machine Clothing: Airbox and Stretch Carriage

Cleanroom Design Engineer, Polipanel Group, Skopje, N. Macedonia Design and construction of cleanrooms for pharmaceutical industries 06/2017 – 08/2019 (2 years 3 months)

- Researched, designed, fabricated, and installed HVAC mechanical equipment and ductwork in cleanrooms to meet client's requirements in both large and small projects.
- Consulted on HVAC system and equipment design for cleanrooms for a wide range of projects, and collaborated with other engineers, project managers, and construction professionals as needed to create and/or modify design parameters.
- Developed and oversaw all aspects of design including the conceptual, basic and detail phases in designing the cleanrooms using CAD software.
- Analysed HVAC systems and equipment for cleanrooms, when necessary, to find inefficiencies or malfunctions and create solutions to optimize performance and increase the efficiency of their operation.

Projects: Cinnagen Ilac & SD5, Dem Ilac, Biosun Peptide, MAM Project, Sinceritas

SKILLS AND TOOLS

Product and Project Management

Project 2019, Excel, Azure DevOps, JIRA

Cloud Administration and DevOps

Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps, Azure Pipelines CI/CD automation Docker, PS/Bash, Yaml, ARM, Git

Programming Languages, Paradigms, and IDEs Java 11, OOP, SQL, Visual Basic 6.0, C# IntelliJ, Eclipse, Visual Studio

Computer Skills

Office 365/Open Office Suite, Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Lightroom, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects), Inkscape, OBS Studio

LANGUAGES

- Macedonian Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- English Professional Proficiency
- German Elementary Proficiency

PUBLICATIONS

- Elicitating, Estimating and Prioritizing an Epic Backlog to deliver Value Part 1
- Elicitating, Estimating and Prioritizing an Epic Backlog to deliver Value Part 2
- The Ultimate Management Sin
- Scrumfall: The fall of Scrum
- The Pitfalls of Project Management Part 1
- The Pitfalls of Project Management Part 2

...and many more in the Articles section of my LinkedIn

APPENDIX – Education Path Resources

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING COURSES

- Java Programming Masterclass for Software Developers by Tim Buchalka
- Clean Coders Video Series Robert C. Martin
- Java Design Patterns & SOLID Design Principles
- Java Application Performance and Memory Management
- Microsoft Azure Administrator (AZ-104)
- Microsoft Azure DevOps Engineer (AZ-400)

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOKS

- Agile Software Development, Principles, Patterns, and Practices Robert C. Martin
- Accelerate The Science of Lean Software and DevOps: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations – Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble, Gene Kim
- Continuous Architecture in Practice: Software Architecture in the Age of Agility and DevOps Murat Erder, Pierre Pureur, Eoin Woods
- Clean Architecture Robert C. Martin

PRODUCT AND PROJECT MANAGEMENT BOOKS

- A Rational Design Process–How and why to Fake It David L. Parnas, Paul C. Clements
- Agile Management for Software Engineering (Applying the TOC) David J Anderson
- Scrum, The Art of Doing Twice the Work in Half the Time Jeff Sutherland
- A Scrum Book, The Spirit of the Game Jeff Sutherland, James O. Coplien
- Peopleware (Productive Projects and Teams) Tom DeMarco, Tim Lister
- Lean Software Development Mary Poppendieck, Tom Poppendieck
- User Stories Applied: For Agile Software Development Mike Cohn
- The Professional Product Owner Don McGreal, Ralph Jocham
- Agile Project Management with Scrum Ken Schwaber
- Agile Product Management with Scrum Roman Pichler
- Agile Estimating and Planning Mike Cohn
- The Five Dysfunctions of a Team Patrick Lencioni
- The Mythical Man-Month Frederick P. Brooks
- Extreme Programming Explained Kent Beck
- Clean Agile: Back to Basics Robert C. Martin
- Business Analysis Body of Knowledge (BABOK)
- User Stories Applied Mike Cohn
- Shape Up Ryan Singer